

Profile

As a Frontend developer with a focus on JavaScript, I have experience developing and maintaining responsive and user-friendly websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I have a strong understanding of the fundamentals of JavaScript and am proficient in using popular front-end framework such as React. I am dedicated to continuously learning and staying up-to-date with the latest technologies and best practices in web development. I have experience working collaboratively with designers and backend developers to create visually appealing and functional web applications. With my strong problem-solving skills and ability to analyze and resolve complex issues, I am confident in my ability to contribute to the success of any team.

Employment History

Full Stack Developer, Freelance

MAY 2023 - PRESENT

- Skilled in developing interactive and responsive user interfaces using React.js and managing application state with Redux, ensuring efficient and scalable frontend architectures.
- Experience in building web applications using modern frontend technologies like React, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS, focusing on delivering intuitive user experiences and optimized performance.
- Familiarity with Node.js for server-side development, enabling the creation of dynamic and data-driven applications. Able to build APIs and integrate with backend services to develop end-to-end solutions.

Frontend Developer, Coding & Company

JANUARY 2023 - APRIL 2023

- Developed and maintained responsive and user-friendly websites using HTML, CSS, and PHP.
- Collaborated with designers and backend developers to create visually appealing and functional web applications.
- Familiarity with version control systems such as Git for efficient and collaborative development.
- Effective communication and interpersonal skills to work effectively in a team
 environment.

Full Stack Developer, Freelance

AUGUST 2022 - JANUARY 2023

- Development of interface and architecture of websites, and implementation of new features and maintenance of applications.
- Management of servers and database for its correct operation
- Guaranteed the functionality of the applications and pages on mobile devices.
- Worked on the scalability of projects.

Full Stack Developer - Internship, Global News Group

JULY 2022 - AUGUST 2022

- Mobile application, focused on generating a correct management of information between employees and the Human Resources sector.
- We worked in a team of 4 developers, in 4 weeks we managed to deliver a correct product and thought of the client's needs.
- React Native, Redux, Node, PostgreSQL

Education

Full Stack Developer, Plataforma 5, Buenos Aires, Argentina

Details

Buenos Aires, C1414BJE Argentina

marianoalvarez66@gmail.com

NATIONALITY

Argentina

DATE OF BIRTH

20/05/1988

Links

Linkedin

Porfolio

Github

Skills

React

JavaScript

HTML & CSS

Redux

React Native

Git

jQuery

GSAP

Bootstrap

Scrum

Agile Methodology

PHP

MySQL

Node.js

Languages

English

Spanish; Castilian

Hobbies

- Music: I learned in a self-taught way to play the drums.
- Calisthenics: I am a teacher of this discipline, giving classes 3 times a week.

Immersive and intensive bootcamp. More than 800 hours of training (400 hours of Pair Programming). Object Oriented Programming (OOP). Construction of applications, implementation of APIs. Realization of 3 projects, one with real clients.

Graphic Design, Da Vinci, Buenos Aires, Argentina

Mastery of an essential software package for every graphic designer (Photoshop, Illustrator and inDesign). Notions of design, art and marketing necessary to develop attractive products for market acceptance.